Guide to the UH Business Manager (McElhinney) Records
University of Houston Libraries
- Legislative Activities, 1958-1963
  - Instructions for Legislative Appropriations, March 1962 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Quarterly Meeting, April 9, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Called Meeting, June 5, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Role and Scope of UH, June 6, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Quarterly Manual, July 9, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - State of Texas Budget Submission 1964-65, July 16, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Council of College Presidents, July 1962 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Report of Budget Hearing, UH Campus, September 6, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Texas Commission on Higher Education, October 8, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Quarterly Meeting, October 8, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - State of Texas Budget Submission 1964-65, October 15, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Higher Ed. Budget Recommendations, October 23, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Called Meeting, October 23, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Meeting, October 23, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Correspondence, Fall 1962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Texas Executive Budget 1964-1965, December 15, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Texas Executive Budget 1964-1965, December 15, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Original Bill & Amendment Reagan Cartwright, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Budget Estimates 1964-1965, January 11, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Legislative Budget Estimates 1964-1965, January 11, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Quarterly Meeting, January 14, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Legislative Budget Recommendations 1964-1965, January 18, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Article IV, Agencies of Public Education, January 21, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Article V, General Provisions, January 21, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Data Supporting Budget Presentation, January 29, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Amendment (SB No. 122 and HB No. 291), January 1963 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Executive Budget Office, January 1963 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Commission on Higher Education Called Meeting, February 8, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Commission on Higher Education Regular Called Quarterly Minutes, February 8, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Commission on Higher Education Tuition, February 21, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Summary of Senate Bill No. 122, February 1963 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Summary of House Bill No. 291, February 1963 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Budget Address to John Connally, March 7, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Texas Governors Budget Recommendations, March 1963 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Agenda, April 8, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - State University and College Pres. Meeting, April 18, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Recommendations, April 26, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - 1963-1965 Biennial Appropriations, April 29, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Biennial Legislative Appropriations, June 1963 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Commission on Higher Ed. Quarterly Meeting, July 8, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Legislative Correspondence General File, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - UH Faculty Salaries, 1961-62 and 1962-63 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - University of Texas, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Tax Support Brochures, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 36)
- Building Files, 1955-1966
  This series, consisting of ninety folders of material, deals with the planning, funding, and construction of the A. D. Bruce Religion Center and the University Center. It is divided into two sub-series, Religious Center and University Center. The bulk of the material dates from 1965 to 1966 and includes subject files, bids, financial records, correspondence, and promotional literature from various companies.
  - Religious Center
    This sub-series, which consists of thirty-four folders, is divided into three sub-sub-series: Subject Files, Architect, and Organ.
    - Subject Files
      The Subject Files are arranged alphabetically by folder title and include planning and fund-raising information.
      - Bradley Washfountain Co., April 26, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Campus Clergy and Counselors, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Cash Requirements, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Contributions for Religious Center Building, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Contributions from Central Lutheran, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Contributions, Roman Catholic, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, Religious Center, 1958-1963 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Decoration and Furnishings, June 1964 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Extension of time, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Farnsworth and Chambers Co., October 3, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Financial Status Reports, February-July 1964 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Funding for Professional Services, March 1964 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - General Correspondence, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Insurance, September 2, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Legal, February-March 1962 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Payments, Architectural Service, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Program – Religion Center Dedication, April 25-May 23, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Proposed Building, Picture Leaflet, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Proposed Religion Center Building, July-December 1961 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Religious Preference Card, Spring 1964 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Architect
      The Architect sub-sub-series relates to architect Frank C. Dill’s work and the Tellepsen Construction Company. Folders are arranged alphabetically.
      - Brochure-Frank C. Dill, Architect, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Contract-Frank C. Dill, Architect, October 1962 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - Cost Estimate-Frank C. Dill, Architect, 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - General Correspondence, Frank C. Dill, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Lockwood, Andrews, and Newman Inc., 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Payments – Tellepsen Construction, Oct. 1963-March 1965 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Specifications-Frank C. Dill, August 21, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - Specifications-Frank C. Dill, August 21, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      - Tellepsen Construction – Contract, August 1963-May 1965 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Organ
      The Organ sub-sub-series relates to the various companies that wanted to receive the contract for the Religious Center organ.
      - Bids – Organ for Religious Center, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Contract – M.P. Meller, Inc., 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Organ – Brochures, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Reuter Organ Company Contract, December 1964-February 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Re-pipe Organ, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - University Center
    This sub-series, which consists of fifty-five folders, is divided into two sub-sub-series, Bids/Worksheets and Subject Files.
    - Bids/Worksheets
      This sub-sub-series includes the bids for various aspects of the University Center and worksheets relating to the various bids.
      - Bid File – Requests, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - Bids and General Correspondence, Nov. 1964-March 1965 (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Worksheets, Group I, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - Worksheets, Group II, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - Worksheets, Group III, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - Worksheets, Group IV, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 40)
      - Worksheets, Group V, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 41)
      - Worksheets, Group VI, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 42)
      - Worksheets, Group VII, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 43)
      - Worksheets, Group VIII, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 44)
      - Worksheets, Group IX, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 45)
      - Worksheets, Group X, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 46)
      - Worksheets, Group XI, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 47)
      - Worksheets, Group XII, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 48)
      - Worksheets, Group XIII, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 49)
      - Worksheets, Group XIV, October 1965 (Box 16, Folder 50)
      - Worksheets, Group XV, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 51)
      - Worksheets, Group XVI, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 52)
      - Worksheets, Group XVII, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 53)
      - Worksheets, Group XVIII, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 54)
      - Worksheets, Group XVIV, November 20, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 55)
      - Worksheets, Group XX, December 10, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 56)
      - Notice to Bidders, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 57)
      - Worksheet-Notice to Bidders-Draperies, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 58)
      - Worksheet-Notice to Bidders-Carpeting and Rugs, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 59)
      - Notice to Bidders and Cover Page, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 60)
      - Bids, Furnishings – American Desk Company, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 61)
      - Bids, Furnishings – The Clegg Company, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 62)
      - Bids, Furnishings – Evans Monical, Inc., January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 63)
      - Bids, Carpet, Rugs – Gibson Floor Covering, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 64)
      - Bids, Carpet, Rug-Fashion Carpet and Interiors, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 65)
      - Bids, Interior Design of Texas, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 66)
      - Bids, Finger Furniture, Inc., January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 67)
      - Bids, Remington -Rand Corp, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 68)
      - Bids, Stewart Office Supply, January 10, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 69)
      - Bids, Texas Office Supply, January 10, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Subject Files
      This sub-sub-series is arranged chronologically and includes the minutes and reports of various committees, which addressed the need for a student center on campus in the late 1950s and early 1960s.
      - Student Union Building Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Proposed Student Union Building, 1956-1958 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Student Union Building Committee, 1956-1958 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Tape Recording – Luncheon Meeting, June 9, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Planning Committee, 1955-1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Tulane University Center, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Staff Study on Housing and Student Life, August 5, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - George Pierce and Abel B. Pierce- Architects, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Application-Loan for Campus Center, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Housing Forms, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Housing Application Forms, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Housing and Home Finance Agency, March 7, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Consultant-William E. Rion-Payments, 1958 and 1963 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Planning Committee Student Surveys, 1961-1963 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Bids Received Mechanical, December 22, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Bids Received Electrical, December 22, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Bids Received Kitchen Equipment, December 22, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Bids Received General Contract, December 23, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - George F. Pierce, Jr. – Architect, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Pierce and Pierce Specifications, Architects, November 16, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Presidents Office, 1947-1973
  This series consists of eighty-nine folders of material and includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, brochures, and other materials generated by or related to the Office of the President. Subjects covered in this series include art on campus, the Clear Lake campus, President Hoffman’s inauguration, and the president’s house. Also included are files with material from General A. D. Bruce, Philip G. Hoffman, and Clanton W. Williams. The materials are divided into the following sub-series: Art, General A.D. Bruce, Clear Lake Campus, Philip G. Hoffman, Inauguration, Clanton W. Williams, and Subject Files. Each sub-series is arranged chronologically.
  - Art
    - Portrait – Roy Gustav Cullen Repaired, November 13, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Jack Key Flanagan – Artist- Re: Portrait, May 1964 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - President’s Committee on Works of Art, February 7, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Art Acquisition Fund – Memo, August 19, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - President’s Committee on Art Acquisitions, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Reconditioning Portraits, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Art Acquisitions Fund, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Benton and Moseley Re: Parietal Rules, February 23, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Letter Re: Sale of Painting “Le Meditation”, November 19, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Memo Re: Registration of Art Work, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Bruce, General A.D.
    - President’s Office, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - President’s Office, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - President’s Office, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Chancellor’s Office, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Chancellor’s Office, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Chancellor’s Office, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Chancellor’s Office, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Newspaper Clippings, Re: Gen. Bruce Retiring, May 1961 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Clear Lake Campus
    - UH at Clear Lake Brochures, November 14, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - UH at Clear Lake, Dr. Alfred R. Neumann, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Clear Lake Campus, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Hoffman, Philip G.
    - President's Office, 1961-62 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - President's Office, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - President's Office, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - President's Office, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - President's Office, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - President's Office, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - President's Office, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - President's Office, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - President's Office, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - President's Office, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Biennial Report of the President, 1963-1965 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Biennial Report of the President, 1965-1967 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Biennial Report of the President, 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Hoffman Subject Files
    - Suniland Furniture Company-Coffee Table, December 18, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - Specifications for Automobiles, November 20, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - President’s Home, Re: Tennis Court, December 20, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - Dr. Philip G. Hoffman-Itinerary, July 1, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Inventory-President’s Home, August 25, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - President’s Contingency Fund, August 31, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - School Management Magazines, September 23, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - Notice: Membership Lists, October 1964 (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Summary Expenditures, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Letter to Mr. Roy Henry Cullen, February 19, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - President’s – Tenure, October 29, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - Letter Agreement – Mackie and Kamrath, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - President’s Discretionary Fund, February 1966 (Box 17, Folder 69)
    - Attorney General’s Office; Re: Medical Office, July 1966 (Box 17, Folder 70)
    - President’s Standing Committees, October 20, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 71)
    - Booklet “The Texas Budget in Brief”, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 72)
    - Memos to President Hoffman, June 2 and July 20, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 73)
    - CFM-Prepare Speech for Meeting, Dallas, January 26 and 27, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 74)
    - Community Relations Meeting, February 19, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 75)
    - Advisory Committee, July 1968 (Box 17, Folder 76)
    - Remarks-General Faculty Meeting, September 13, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 77)
    - Higher Education Executive Associates, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 78)
    - Parkwood House Letter Re: Purchasing, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 79)
    - Mr. Paul E. Purser, Special Assistant, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 80)
    - Proposed Fringe Benefits, April 1, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 81)
    - Philip G. Hoffman’s Statement on Grand Jury Probe, May 14, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 82)
    - Campus Disturbance, May 17, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 83)
    - Committees, October 19, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 84)
    - Summary Statement, October 1969 (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - NASULGC – Executive Committee, December 8, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence – Campus Security, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Memos to President Philip Hoffman, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Contract-Presidents Residence, May 1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Assistant-Mr. Jerome M. Peschke, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - S.W. Bell Telephone Co. – Credit Cards, January 12, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - President’s Consultation Committee, March 5, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Dr. Allen Commander – Assistant, July 17, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Washington Reports, March 28, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Baker and Botts, Attorneys, November 14, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Memorandum to Philip Hoffman, August-December 1972 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Office of Assistant -Dr. Allen Commander, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "What Makes a University Great?," Acta Diurna, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Inauguration
    - Presidential Inauguration Samples, 1947-1955 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Presidential Inauguration Samples, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Presidential Inauguration, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Presidential Inauguration Committee Meetings, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Presidential Inauguration Committee Ceremony, February-October 1962 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Presidential Inauguration Committee Programs, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Williams, Clanton W.
    - Academic Affairs Office, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Academic Affairs Office, 1955-1956 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Academic Affairs Office, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - President’s Office, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - President’s Office, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - President’s Office, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 25)
- Houston College for Negroes, 1945-1948
  This series consists of thirty folders of material, dating from 1945 to 1948 and includes receipts, financial records, correspondence, and memoranda. The bulk of the material dates from 1945 to 1947. Included are records from fund-raising efforts for construction of buildings on the campus, as well as financial records for the Houston College for Negroes.
  - Pledges #1601 – #1615, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Pledges #1616 – #1623, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Pledges #1801 – #1815, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Pledges #1816 – #1830, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Pledges #1831 – #1850, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Pledges #1851 – [#1865], 1945 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Pledges #1866 – #1880, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Pledges #1881 – #1900, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Pledges #1901 – #1915, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Pledges #1916 – #1930, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Pledges #1918 – #1950, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Pledges #1951 – #1945 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Pledges #1967 – [#1980], 1945 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Pledges #1981 – [#1997], 1945 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Building Fund Book 1, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Building Fund Book 2, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Bank Account Notices, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Accounts Receivable Veterans, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Accounts Receivable Veterans, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Accounts Receivable, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Wheeler Ave. Sale of Land, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - General Correspondence, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Texas State University Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Vocational Building Bids, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Sanitary Sewer, Bids, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Temporary Housing, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Trailers, Preparing Site, bids, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - City of Houston, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - Houston College for Negroes Building, 1945-1947 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Trailers, 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - Vocational Building, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 57)